<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Professional :: AWS Solution Architect</title>
    <link>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/index.html</link>
    <description>Please connect at 2pm by clicking here Recording Link Table of Contents (30 Hrs) 1. Introduction Overview of AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Professional Exam structure and objectives Prerequisites and recommended knowledge 2. AWS Well-Architected Framework Pillars: Operational Excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance Efficiency, Cost Optimization Design principles and best practices 3. Advanced Networking VPC peering and Transit Gateway PrivateLink and Direct Connect Route tables and NAT gateways Hybrid connectivity patterns 4. Compute Services EC2 instances and placement groups Auto Scaling strategies Lambda architecture patterns Container services: ECS, EKS, Fargate 5. Storage and Databases S3 advanced features: lifecycle, replication, cross-region access Glacier, EBS optimizations, FSx RDS, Aurora, DynamoDB, Redshift configurations Caching strategies with ElastiCache 6. Security and Compliance IAM advanced configurations Security groups, NACLs, and KMS AWS Organizations, SCPs, and resource policies Audit and compliance services: CloudTrail, Config 7. Monitoring and Management CloudWatch, CloudTrail, and AWS Config Health dashboards and reporting Automated alerts and runbooks Resource tagging strategies 8. High Availability and Fault Tolerance Multi-AZ and multi-region deployments Failover strategies Disaster Recovery Planning (RPO, RTO) 9. Performance Optimization Load balancing with ALB, NLB, and Gateway Caching, replication, and compression techniques Architecture patterns for high throughput and low latency 10. Cost Optimization Reserved instances and spot instances Cost Explorer and budgets Resource scaling and right-sizing Cost-effective design patterns 11. Migration and Hybrid Architectures Lift-and-shift and refactoring strategies Data migration tools: DMS, Snowball, Transfer Family Integrating on-premises and cloud workloads 12. Disaster Recovery and Backup Strategies RTO/RPO planning Backup mechanisms across AWS services Cross-region failover architectures 13. Advanced Application Architectures Event-driven architectures Microservices and API Gateways Serverless workflows and best practices 14. Exam Practice Sample questions Scenario-based problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with AWS</title>
      <link>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/getting-started-with-the-course/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/getting-started-with-the-course/index.html</guid>
      <description>Learn the foundational concepts of AWS.&#xA;AWS Account Regions Availability Zones (AZs) Edge Locations Support AWS Account Your AWS Account is your unique identity in the AWS ecosystem. It acts as a container for your resources, billing, and permissions.&#xA;Manages access to AWS services Tracks usage and billing Supports multiple users via IAM (Identity and Access Management) Can be organized into Organizations for managing multiple accounts AWS Regions An AWS Region is a geographically distinct area containing multiple data centers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS IAM (Identity and Access Management)</title>
      <link>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/02/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/02/index.html</guid>
      <description>Objectives [Understand the fundamentals of AWS IAM and its components] Learn how to manage users, groups, roles, and permissions securely Implement best practices for access control and identity federation Configure permissions for services like EC2. 📚 AWS IAM (Identity and Access Management) AWS IAM is a web service that helps you securely control access to AWS services and resources for your users.&#xA;✅ What is AWS IAM? AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) enables you to:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Imp Link</title>
      <link>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/projects-tasks/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/projects-tasks/index.html</guid>
      <description>AWS Solutions Architect – Professional Course Curriculum Lesson 00 – Course Overview An introduction to the course objectives, structure, and exam preparation strategies. Understand the value of AWS architecture and the skills you will gain.&#xA;📘 Sample Questions&#xA;What are the main pillars of AWS architecture? How should you prepare for the AWS Solutions Architect – Professional exam? 🔗 Learn More&#xA;AWS Certification Overview Lesson 01 – AWS Overview Learn the basics of AWS cloud computing, global infrastructure, core services, and deployment models. Understand how AWS helps build scalable and secure applications.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>