<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Professional :: AWS Solution Architect</title>
    <link>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/index.html</link>
    <description>Table of Contents Getting started with the course Multi-Account Based Architectures VPC Endpoints Load Balancing Solutions Database Primer Application Integration Networking Primer Security Services Deployment Services Logs and Analytics Route53 and Hybrid DNS Container Services Migration Planning Cost Optimizations Storage Services Systems Manager &amp; Integration Services CDN, API Gateways and Lambda Machine Learning Services Practice Tests Section 1: Getting started with the course Section 2: Multi-Account Based Architectures Section 3: VPC Endpoints Section 4: Load Balancing Solutions Section 5: Database Primer Section 6: Application Integration Section 7: Networking Primer Section 8: Security Services Section 9: Deployment Services Section 10: Logs and Analytics Section 11: Route53 and Hybrid DNS Section 12: Container Services Section 13: Migration Planning Section 14: Cost Optimizations Section 15: Storage Services Section 16: Systems Manager &amp; Integration Services Section 17: CDN, API Gateways and Lambda Section 18: Machine Learning Services Section 19: Practice Tests</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with AWS</title>
      <link>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/getting-started-with-the-course/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/getting-started-with-the-course/index.html</guid>
      <description>This guide introduces the foundational concepts of AWS, including AWS Account, Regions, Availability Zones (AZs), Edge Locations, and Support. Understanding these will help you navigate AWS’s global infrastructure confidently.&#xA;AWS Account Your AWS Account is your unique identity in the AWS ecosystem. It acts as a container for your resources, billing, and permissions.&#xA;Manages access to AWS services Tracks usage and billing Supports multiple users via IAM (Identity and Access Management) Can be organized into Organizations for managing multiple accounts AWS Regions An AWS Region is a geographically distinct area containing multiple data centers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Multi-Account Strategy</title>
      <link>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/02/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://github.com/nirpendra83/aws-doc.git/02/index.html</guid>
      <description>Managing multiple AWS accounts is a best practice for organizations looking to improve security, billing, and resource isolation. The AWS Multi-Account Strategy helps you organize your cloud environment efficiently.&#xA;Legacy Approach: Single AWS Account Before multi-account strategies became popular, many organizations used a single AWS account for all workloads, environments, and teams.&#xA;Challenges of the Legacy Approach: Security risks: Lack of isolation increases blast radius if credentials are compromised. Billing confusion: Difficult to track costs per project, environment, or team. Resource limits: AWS service quotas apply per account, limiting scalability. Complex permissions: Managing IAM policies for diverse teams and environments becomes complicated. Operational risks: Accidental resource changes can impact production workloads. Why Use Multiple AWS Accounts? Isolation of workloads: Separate development, testing, and production environments. Security boundaries: Limit blast radius if one account is compromised. Billing clarity: Track costs by team, project, or environment. Simplified compliance: Enforce policies and audits more easily. Resource limits: Avoid hitting AWS service limits by distributing resources across accounts. Key Components of a Multi-Account Strategy AWS Organizations Centralized management of multiple AWS accounts. Use Service Control Policies (SCPs) to set permission guardrails. Consolidated billing for all linked accounts. Automated account creation and lifecycle management. Account Structure Models 1. Environment-Based Account Name Purpose Prod Production workloads Dev Development environment Test Testing and QA 2. Business Unit-Based Account Name Purpose Marketing Marketing projects Finance Financial systems Engineering Engineering projects 3. Application-Based Account Name Purpose App-A Application A workloads App-B Application B workloads Best Practices Centralize logging and monitoring: Use AWS CloudTrail and AWS Config aggregated in a dedicated account. Use cross-account roles: Enable secure access between accounts. Automate account provisioning: Use AWS Control Tower or custom automation. Implement guardrails: Apply SCPs to enforce security policies. Tag consistently: Use tags for cost allocation and resource management. Visual Overview AWS Organizations │ ├── Security Account (centralized logging, monitoring) ├── Shared Services Account (DNS, directory services) ├── Prod Account(s) ├── Dev Account(s) └── Test Account(s)&#xD;Summary A well-planned multi-account strategy enhances security, operational efficiency, and cost control in AWS environments. AWS Organizations and related tools make managing multiple accounts easier and more secure.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>